# Keisuke Umezawa

Email: keisuke.umezawa[at]gmail.com

Twitter: [@kumezawa ](https://twitter.com/kumezawa )

Blog(ja): Hatena Blog Blog(en): Medium

GitHub: github.com/keisuke-umezawa Software Engineer / Machine Learning Engineer

## Profile Summary

Software and machine learning engineer with the experiences in financial modeling, search engine development and recommendation engine development. In most cases, I led teams to accomplish the targets by sharing objectives, requirements and schedules. When assigning tasks to someone, I think that the most important thing is delegating ownership and responsibility to motivate them.

# Work Experience

#### 2018.3-(Current) Engineer, Chief Engineering Manager: AlpacaJapan, Japan

- · Leading model development for AlpacaForecast (Forex market prediction) using deep learning with data scientists
- Developed trading backtesting engine "AlpacaDB/backlight" to standardize evaluation method
- Standardize development process and team management: introduced ticketing system, scrum meeting, 1on1 and guidelines for development and communication

### 2017.3-(Current) Chainer Evangelist: Preferred Networks, Japan

- Responsible for increasing people who uses "Chainer"
  - Organizing chug (Chainer User Group)
  - Holding talks about the deep learning and its framework "Chainer"
  - Improving the documentation and tutorials
  - Holded more than 10 hands-ons and meetups

### **2016.8-2018.3 Engineer**: Yahoo Japan Corporation, Japan

- Developed inhouse search engines for the ad and media services
  - developing inhouse search engine for advertisement distribution system with C++, Java and Python
  - Instructed agile software development such as Scrum
  - Instructed C++ cording in the team
- Led and productized inhouse recommendation engine for the media services
  - Leaded a data scientist and system engineers to build new deep learning based recommendation system
  - Responsible for satisfying requirements, architecture design and team management

## 2014.4-2016.8 Quantitative Analyst and Model Developer: the Bank of Tokyo Mitsubishi UFJ, Japan

Developed derivatives pricing model and risk management system with C++

#### Education

**2012-2014 MSc, Department of Mechano-Informatics**; Graduate School of Information Science and Technology, the University of Tokyo, Japan

human motion recognition and robot motion generation by HMM

**2012.5-2012.8** Internship, at Learning Algorithms and Systems Laboratory (LASA); the Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne (EPFL), Switzerland

2008-2012 BSc, Department of Mechano-Informatics; Faculty of Engineering, the University of Tokyo, Japan

# Technical Experience

# Product Management

### Managed teams using following ideas:

- Delegating ownership and responsibility
- 1on1
- Agile Methodology (Scrum/Kanban)
- Ticketing tools s.t. Jira, Github projects

# Programming Languages

first-lang: experienced items as follows with C++ and python

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Design of API
- Multi-thread programming
- C++ meta programming
- Functional programming

Basic knowledge of C++, Python, Java, sh/bash. And a fun of Rust.

### System Archtecture Development Tools Machine Learning Algorithms

Basic experience of RDS, KVS, Message Queue, Search Engine, Restful API

Basic experience of GitHub, Docker, k8s, ci/cd

### Implementation Experience

- linear regression, logistic regression, k-NN, k-means, Hidden Markov Model
- Deep Learning Application
  - CNN, RNN, word2vec, seq2seq, DCGAN, WaveNet, etc

### **Use Experience**

• SVM, Ensembler, Logistic Regression, etc

### Publication

A. L. P. Ureche, K. Umezawa, Y. Nakamura and A. Billard, "Task Parameterization Using Continuous Constraints Extracted From Human Demonstrations," in IEEE Transactions on Robotics, vol. 31, no. 6, pp. 1458-1471, Dec. 2015. link

### Extra Section

- Certificates
  - IPA Database Specialist
- Human Languages:
  - Japanese (native speaker)
  - English (business level)